Hello. Today we're in the Polygon
Samurai Empire pack and I'm going to be
showing you a couple of things about
setting up and using the Unity terrains.
First of all, a couple of
troubleshooting tips. If your terrain is
shiny like you see here, then what you
need to do is go to the base texture and
change the compression from high quality
to normal quality. And if you've opened
up Unity 6 and you've got this shadowy
bug when you try to paint textures, one
of the things you can try to do is go to
your project settings and change from
DX12 to DX11. As for setting up the
terrain itself, what you want to do is
create a 3D object terrain and go to the
terrain settings and change the scale a
lot lower because it's quite big by
default, especially the height. Then
what I like to do is to change the
terrain height because by default it is
at its lowest point. So what you want to
do is raise it a little bit and then set
height. You can shift click to get a
sample of what height you want and then
just cover the whole terrain. Then as
you can see here, you can raise the
terrain up and also dig down. This is
also now a good opportunity to test your
maximum height and depth and tweak as
necessary. Next, we need to add some
terrain textures. So, we're going to in
your project window, create a terrain
layer, create a grass, for example, and
then just select the texture and the
normal map. And then we're going to come
back to the terrain settings and add a
new terrain layer. Add any extra layers
that you might need. And you can use the
brushes tab to change how the tool
paints onto the terrain. Here I've
grabbed a couple of buildings from the
demo scene. And as you can see, painting
on a few different layers of different
textures really helps set it into the
scene. You can very quickly improve the
look by adding in some ground prefabs
like rocks and gravels and tiles to add
that 3D element that really sells it as
part of the world. For trees, you can
either manually place the prefabs or you
can go to the tree tab and add the
prefabs and use the terrain tools to
quickly paint them in at different
scales and rotations. For grass, you can
either use the same technique if you
have prefabs. Uh, in this case, I'm
using a grass texture and using the
builtin Unity terrain grass system. It's
best to paint a patch of grass first and
then modify it from there before
continuing to dress the rest of the
scene. You can also add them as a detail
mesh, but it does not support LOD
groups, so it can be a little heavier.
For our maps, we do manually place all
of our prefabs just to make sure it is
in the exact spot that we want it to be.
But if you are making a bigger scene, it
makes sense to use some tools to help
speed up the process. Final step to
improve the look is to add some camera
post effects. If you're using the
universal render pipeline, you need to
add a global volume to your scene. And
from there, you can add overrides. And
I'd recommend a baseline of bloom, color
adjustments, vignette, and lift gamma
gain. That's all for today. I hope you
have found this video helpful, and good
luck with your world creation.